{
    "id": "ebde2718183f4faabceff3437ae7553f",
    "title": "Infinitive Complements Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "05afe00f00964682ad1b1962d9ad44dc",
            "title": "Infinitive Complements Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She didn’t want ……………………",
                    "description": "Want is usually followed by object + infinitive. That-clauses are not normally used after want.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that I go",
                        "me to go",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They don’t allow ………………………….",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "that visitors access the library",
                        "visitors to access the library"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I didn’t ask ………………………….. the tickets.",
                    "description": "That-clauses are unusual after ask.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that you buy",
                        "you to buy",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why don’t you let me ………………………?",
                    "description": "Some verbs are followed by object + infinitive without to. Let is one of them.",
                    "answers": [
                        "explain",
                        "to explain",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I watched the kids ………………………… in the garden.",
                    "description": "Watch is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "play",
                        "to play",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I heard her ………………………….. the door and go out.",
                    "description": "Heard is followed by an infinitive without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "open",
                        "to open",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I suggested ………………………… consult a doctor.",
                    "description": "Suggest cannot be followed by object + infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "her to",
                        "that she should",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are advised ……………………………. early.",
                    "description": "Passive forms of advise can be followed by object + infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "come",
                        "to come",
                        "that you should come"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Is it the first time ……………………………. here?",
                    "description": "Here the expression first time has no subject relationship with the following verb and hence the infinitive structure is not possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for you to stay here",
                        "that you have stayed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is the oldest athlete …………………… an Olympic medal.",
                    "description": "Superlatives can usually be followed by an infinitive structure. The meaning is very similar to an identifying relative clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "ever to win",
                        "who has ever won",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I saw him .................................... the money.",
                    "description": "After see, the infinitive is used without to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "steal",
                        "to steal",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You don't look happy ....................................... me.",
                    "description": "Happy is followed by an infinitive with to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "seeing",
                        "to see",
                        "to seeing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}